thefreethoughtproject.com 2019-12-22

# Read detailed website privacy policy of The Free Thought Project

## Privacy Policy:

The Free Thought Project (“ **Free Thought Project** “) operates https://thefreethoughtproject.com/ and may operate other websites. It is The Free Thought Project’s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our websites.

### Website Visitors

Like most website operators, Free Thought Project collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. The Free Thought Project’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how The Free Thought Project’s visitors use its website. From time to time, Free Thought Project may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

Free Thought Project also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments on https://thefreethoughtproject.com/ blogs/sites. Free Thought Project only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below, except that commenter IP addresses and email addresses are visible and disclosed to the administrators of the blog/site where the comment was left.

### Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to The Free Thought Project’s websites choose to interact with Free Thought Project in ways that require Free Thought Project to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Free Thought Project gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up at <https://thefreethoughtproject.com/> to provide a username and email address. Those who engage in transactions with Free Thought Project are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal and financial information required to process those transactions. In each case, Free Thought Project collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with Free Thought Project. Free Thought Project does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

### Aggregated Statistics

Free Thought Project may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. Free Thought Project may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, Free Thought Project does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please see: <https://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>

### Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

Free Thought Project discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on The Free Thought Project’s behalf or to provide services available at The Free Thought Project’s websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using The Free Thought Project’s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. Free Thought Project will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, Free Thought Project discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when Free Thought Project believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Free Thought Project, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of an Free Thought Project website and have supplied your email address, Free Thought Project may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with Free Thought Project and our products. If you send us a request (for example via email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Free Thought Project takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

### Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Free Thought Project uses cookies to help Free Thought Project identify and track visitors, their usage of Free Thought Project website, and their website access preferences. Free Thought Project visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using The Free Thought Project’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of The Free Thought Project’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

### Business Transfers

If Free Thought Project, or substantially all of its assets, were acquired, or in the unlikely event that Free Thought Project goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of Free Thought Project may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy.

### Ads

Ads appearing on any of our websites may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by Free Thought Project and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

### Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Free Thought Project may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in The Free Thought Project’s sole discretion. Free Thought Project encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. If you have a https://thefreethoughtproject.com/ account, you might also receive an alert informing you of these changes. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.
